<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://blog.popekim.com/en/feed/personal.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://blog.popekim.com/en/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2026-02-27T00:30:58+00:00</updated><id>https://blog.popekim.com/en/feed/personal.xml</id><title type="html">PPMC | Personal</title><subtitle>Pope Kim&apos;s Blog</subtitle><author><name>Pope Kim</name></author><entry><title type="html">The Repeating 3-Week Pattern: What I Learned by Finishing the Last Course Myself</title><link href="https://blog.popekim.com/en/2025/11/21/repeating-3week-pattern.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Repeating 3-Week Pattern: What I Learned by Finishing the Last Course Myself" /><published>2025-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://blog.popekim.com/en/2025/11/21/repeating-3week-pattern</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.popekim.com/en/2025/11/21/repeating-3week-pattern.html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://pocu.academy">POCU video lectures</a> come with transcripts that someone already cleaned up once. The content is mostly accurate, but the line breaks and punctuation are all over the place. To use them in an automated pipeline, they need to be reorganized. One student had been helping me with that work for several years on a part-time basis.</p>

<p>He worked on multiple courses, and strangely, the pattern was always the same.</p>

<!--more-->

<p>He did exactly 3 weeks of content very well. Then he disappeared.</p>

<p>A few months later he would reappear, apologize, finish another 3 weeks, and disappear again. It did not matter which course it was; the pattern repeated every single time.</p>

<p>And now that I think about it, it was not because he was lazy. It is simply that the work itself was the kind that wears people out.</p>

<p>I finally understood this very clearly when I tried doing it myself.</p>

<h2 id="the-last-course-and-an-8-month-gap">The last course, and an 8-month gap</h2>

<p>This time, the task he received was truly the last remaining course. Finishing this one would complete a multi-year transcript improvement project. As usual, he completed the first 3 weeks perfectly.</p>

<p>Then he disappeared again. Three weeks later he showed up, extremely apologetic. I could feel his guilt and pressure right through the messages. That heavy feeling of "I know I should do it, but I just cannot get myself to do it."</p>

<p>And after finishing another 3 weeks, he disappeared again. This time, the gap was especially long. About 8 months.</p>

<p>The weight of the guilt he had shown before felt too heavy. I realized it would not be good for either of us to drag this out any longer.</p>

<p>So I decided to finish the last course myself.</p>

<h2 id="and-then-i-also-got-stuck-exactly-at-the-3-week-mark">And then… I also got stuck exactly at the 3-week mark</h2>

<p>Once I started working on it, I realized something funny. I also stopped right at the 3-week mark.</p>

<p>The beginning went smoothly. Cleaning up sentences felt satisfying, and the progress was visible. I thought, "This is going pretty well." The speed was good too.</p>

<p>But the moment I crossed the 3-week line, suddenly nothing was left except endless repetition. The interest vanished. My motivation and energy drained at the same time. I even started disliking myself for sitting at the desk.</p>

<p>That is when I realized:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>"Ah… this must have been exactly what he felt every time he stopped at 3 weeks."</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Honestly, I had quietly wondered, "Why can he never finish it?" But once I experienced the same block, I had no right to judge him.</p>

<p>To be even more honest, he was better than me. At least he had the courage to apologize and come back after a few months. I was just annoyed at myself.</p>

<h2 id="to-keep-going-i-started-stacking-reasons">To keep going, I started stacking reasons</h2>

<p>Even so, this time I could not run away. This was the final course. If I dropped it, no one else would pick it up.</p>

<p>So I started collecting reasons to pull myself back to the desk.</p>

<h3 id="1-finishing-this-opens-the-automation-pipeline">1) Finishing this opens the automation pipeline</h3>
<p>It is annoying now, but finishing this task will reduce future annoyance hundreds of times over.</p>

<h3 id="2-i-cannot-enjoy-fun-projects-if-this-is-left-unfinished">2) I cannot enjoy fun projects if this is left unfinished</h3>
<p>New lectures, system development, interesting experiments… I want to do all of them, but this unfinished task keeps weighing on my mind.</p>

<h3 id="3-and-coincidentally-i-was-sick-for-a-few-days">3) And coincidentally, I was sick for a few days</h3>
<p>Strangely, mentally intensive work becomes impossible when I feel unwell, but simple repetitive work actually becomes easier. On the day my condition was the worst, this task progressed the fastest.</p>

<p>Holding onto these reasons, I decided to switch into machine mode again.</p>

<h2 id="in-the-end-i-became-a-machine-once-more">In the end, I became a machine once more</h2>

<p>People have often told me since I was young that I seem like a machine. I could never tell whether it was a compliment or an insult. But working on this again reminded me why they say that.</p>

<p>I am someone who suppresses emotions well, and once I decide to do something boring and repetitive, I push through it until the end. Emotions can be processed later.</p>

<p>So I finished the rest in just 5 days.</p>

<p>Truly like a machine.</p>

<h2 id="if-i-feel-less-pain-doing-something-others-find-painful-maybe-that-is-my-job">"If I feel less pain doing something others find painful, maybe that is my job"</h2>

<p>After saving the final file, I remembered something from the book Atomic Habits. I am paraphrasing, but the idea was this:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>What matters is not whether you like the work, but whether you feel the pain less than others do. If you can endure something that others struggle with, that might be the work you are meant to do.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>That was exactly the case with this transcript-cleaning task.</p>

<p>For many people, this kind of work is unbearably boring and painful. But I am, unfortunately, someone who feels that pain a little less. So I was the one who ended up finishing this long project.</p>

<p>It is not something to brag about. It is simply how I am wired. You could call it persistence, or stubbornness, or if we are being very honest… just being a bit rigid.</p>

<p>Still, someone had to finish this work, and it happened to be me.</p>

<p>And now, finally, I can move on to the fun things with a lighter heart.</p>]]></content><author><name>Pope Kim</name></author><category term="personal" /><category term="dev-diary" /><category term="dev" /><category term="pocu" /><category term="simplicity" /><category term="time-management" /><category term="life-advice" /><category term="wisdom" /><category term="book" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[POCU video lectures come with transcripts that someone already cleaned up once. The content is mostly accurate, but the line breaks and punctuation are all over the place. To use them in an automated pipeline, they need to be reorganized. One student had been helping me with that work for several years on a part-time basis. He worked on multiple courses, and strangely, the pattern was always the same.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Engineering in Plain Sight Review: A New Way of Seeing the World</title><link href="https://blog.popekim.com/en/2025/09/02/engineering-in-plain-sight-review.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Engineering in Plain Sight Review: A New Way of Seeing the World" /><published>2025-09-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-09-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://blog.popekim.com/en/2025/09/02/engineering-in-plain-sight-review</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.popekim.com/en/2025/09/02/engineering-in-plain-sight-review.html"><![CDATA[<p>One day, while browsing the shelves at the library, I stumbled upon a book that caught my eye. The title was <em>Engineering in Plain Sight</em> (by Grady Hillhouse). Honestly, at first I just thought the illustrations were pretty, and the first few pages looked fun, so I picked it up lightly, assuming it was just some kind of illustrated reference book.</p>

<p>But the more I read, the more surprised I became. It wasn't just a catalog of "roads, bridges, drains," but a book that revealed in a completely different light the things we've <strong>taken for granted since birth, simply because they've always been there.</strong></p>

<p>As I turned the pages, I realized that all of this infrastructure exists thanks to <em>design, labor, and government investment</em>. Before, I would vaguely think, "Managing all these roads and structures must require a lot of taxes. Taxes aren't a waste." But this book made that thought more concrete and real. It's not just that "it costs a lot of money," but I came to understand <strong>the principles, the methods, and the reasons why maintenance is essential.</strong></p>

<h2 id="power-and-communication-networks">Power and Communication Networks</h2>

<p>The early chapters cover <strong>power and communication networks</strong>, and this is where my perspective started to change. The electricity and internet we use daily without a second thought are, in fact, supported by massive infrastructure. What impressed me most was how the story moved from <strong>older communication networks all the way to modern cellular towers.</strong> From the cables strung along utility poles to the silver masts scattered throughout the city, I realized these weren't just random or decorative objects. Suddenly, ordinary scenery began to take on meaning.</p>

<h2 id="roads-and-tunnels">Roads and Tunnels</h2>

<p>The middle chapters focus on <strong>roads and tunnels.</strong> I never realized how much engineering went into the asphalt we drive on every day. Drainage design, paving materials, even the way lane markings are drawn—all of it has a reason. The tunnel section, with its explanation of ventilation systems, lighting, and fire escape passages, was especially eye-opening. I used to think of tunnels as nothing more than "cramped spaces," but now when I pass through one, I notice the ceiling fans and realize those emergency exits aren't just for show.</p>

<h2 id="water-supply-and-sewage-yes-poop">Water Supply and Sewage (Yes, Poop!)</h2>

<p>My personal favorite section was the one about <strong>water supply and sewage—yes, the poop chapter!</strong> I always thought clean water came out of the tap and wastewater just went "down the drain," but behind that is centuries of accumulated engineering. The book's diagrams of pipes, treatment processes, and purification facilities made me realize, "Wow, it's thanks to this complex and carefully designed system that we can live comfortably and safely." Honestly, it was so fascinating that I found myself chuckling while reading. <em>"This is the hidden world of poop!"</em> 😂</p>

<h2 id="construction">Construction</h2>

<p>The final chapter (Chapter 8) covers <strong>construction</strong>, and this part felt a little underwhelming. Heavy machinery and construction sites are interesting in their own right, but coming right after the unforgettable sewage chapter, it felt less impactful by comparison. Not bad, but for me, Chapter 7 was so strong that Chapter 8 felt more like a bonus.</p>

<h2 id="closing-the-book">Closing the Book</h2>

<p>After finishing this book, my perspective has definitely changed. Where before I only vaguely thought "this must cost a lot of taxes," now I connect what I see with the <strong>specific systems and human effort</strong> behind it all. When I walk down the street, manhole covers, traffic lights, drains, and cell towers all catch my eye, and I think, "Ah, that's exactly what I saw in the book." It's become a private little joy. Others might pass by without noticing, but now I know the meaning—and that's surprisingly fun.</p>

<p>More than anything, this book gave me a sense of <strong>humility and gratitude.</strong> From the unseen sewage pipes carrying waste to the steel frameworks that hold up our cities, it's thanks to the expertise and hard work of countless people that I can live safely and comfortably each day.</p>

<p>That's why I want to recommend this book especially to developers like me, who spend our lives tapping on keyboards. Don't just stare at the virtual world inside a computer. Turn your eyes to the real world beneath your feet. Step away from the "shallow perspective of a software engineer" and, at least for a moment, adopt the mindset of a <strong>civil engineer hauling sewage</strong> to keep the city running. That is the greatest gift this book has to offer.</p>

<p>After all, we live in the <strong>real world, don't we?</strong></p>

<p>So I can say this with confidence:</p>

<p>👉 <em>Engineering in Plain Sight</em> — definitely worth a read.</p>]]></content><author><name>Pope Kim</name></author><category term="personal" /><category term="book" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[One day, while browsing the shelves at the library, I stumbled upon a book that caught my eye. The title was Engineering in Plain Sight (by Grady Hillhouse). Honestly, at first I just thought the illustrations were pretty, and the first few pages looked fun, so I picked it up lightly, assuming it was just some kind of illustrated reference book.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why Tipping Culture in Canada Needs to Go</title><link href="https://blog.popekim.com/en/2023/02/18/why-tipping-culture-in-canada-needs-to-go.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why Tipping Culture in Canada Needs to Go" /><published>2023-02-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-02-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://blog.popekim.com/en/2023/02/18/why-tipping-culture-in-canada-needs-to-go</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.popekim.com/en/2023/02/18/why-tipping-culture-in-canada-needs-to-go.html"><![CDATA[<p>Tipping culture is a contentious topic across the globe, and Canada is no exception. While tipping may be seen as a way to show appreciation for good service, it has become a problematic and unsustainable practice in Canada. In this blog post, I will explore the issue of tipping culture in Canada, as well as how it compares to other countries around the world.</p>

<p>One important point to note is that food service workers in Canada are entitled to the minimum wage, unlike in the United States where the federal minimum wage for tipped workers is much lower than the regular minimum wage. While this may alleviate some of the issues with tipping culture in Canada, it does not eliminate them entirely.</p>

<p>Firstly, tipping puts an undue burden on the customer. It is the responsibility of the employer to pay their employees a fair wage, and it is not up to the customer to make up the difference. Relying on customers to pay a large portion of a worker's salary creates an uneven playing field for employees, where their wages can vary depending on how generous the customers are feeling that day. This inconsistency is particularly unfair to those who work in the service industry, where they may not have the same level of control over their tips as those in other industries.</p>

<p>Secondly, tipping culture can create an unnecessary social pressure on the customer. Customers are expected to tip, even if they received poor service or if the tipping amount is not clear. This pressure can lead to awkward social situations where the customer may feel obligated to tip, even if they cannot afford to. Additionally, tipping culture can lead to discrimination based on factors such as race, gender, and age. Studies have shown that servers receive higher tips from customers who are white, male, and middle-aged, which creates an unfair playing field for those who do not fit into those categories.</p>

<p>Lastly, tipping culture can create an unsustainable work environment for those in the service industry. The uncertainty of tips can create a lot of stress and financial insecurity for workers. It can also incentivize employers to pay lower wages, as they know their employees will make up the difference through tips. This leads to a cycle where workers are expected to work longer hours or take on multiple jobs to make ends meet, which can lead to burnout and a lack of work-life balance.</p>

<p>It is worth noting that tipping culture varies widely around the world. While Canada and the United States are known for their reliance on tips, there are many countries where tipping is not expected or is even considered rude. In some countries, a service charge may be automatically included in the bill, eliminating the need for customers to calculate a tip. In other countries, it is customary to round up the bill to the nearest whole number as a gesture of appreciation for good service.</p>

<p>In conclusion, while tipping culture may be deeply ingrained in certain countries like Canada and the United States, it is important to recognize that it is not a universal practice. By understanding the nuances of tipping culture around the world, we can work towards creating more equitable and sustainable systems for workers in the service industry. However, in Canada, it is clear that tipping culture is a problematic and unsustainable practice that should be thrown away. Employers should be responsible for paying their employees a fair wage, and customers should not feel pressured to tip.</p>

<p>Instead, a more equitable and sustainable system would involve including a service charge in the price of the meal, which would be distributed fairly among all workers. This would eliminate the need for customers to calculate a tip, and provide a stable and fair income for those in the industry. Employers would then be responsible for paying their employees a proper wage that reflects the value of their work. Other countries have already embraced this approach, and there is no reason why Canada cannot do the same. It's time to move towards a more equitable and sustainable system for the benefit of all involved.</p>]]></content><author><name>Pope Kim</name></author><category term="personal" /><category term="culture" /><category term="money" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tipping culture is a contentious topic across the globe, and Canada is no exception. While tipping may be seen as a way to show appreciation for good service, it has become a problematic and unsustainable practice in Canada. In this blog post, I will explore the issue of tipping culture in Canada, as well as how it compares to other countries around the world.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Learning New Knowledge is Easy</title><link href="https://blog.popekim.com/en/2014/02/12/learning-new-knowledge-is-easy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Learning New Knowledge is Easy" /><published>2014-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://blog.popekim.com/en/2014/02/12/learning-new-knowledge-is-easy</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.popekim.com/en/2014/02/12/learning-new-knowledge-is-easy.html"><![CDATA[<p>learning new knowledge is easy, but changing old habits is hard.</p>]]></content><author><name>Pope Kim</name></author><category term="personal" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[learning new knowledge is easy, but changing old habits is hard.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Snow Effect in Google+ Photo</title><link href="https://blog.popekim.com/en/2013/12/23/snow-effect-in-googleplus-photo.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Snow Effect in Google+ Photo" /><published>2013-12-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-12-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://blog.popekim.com/en/2013/12/23/snow-effect-in-googleplus-photo</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.popekim.com/en/2013/12/23/snow-effect-in-googleplus-photo.html"><![CDATA[<p>I didn't know Google+'s Auto Awesome mode does snow effects too. It was a pleasant surprise to find out what it did to a picture I took recently. It would make a good x-mas card :)</p>

<p><img src="/en/assets/img/2013/12/00.gif" alt="img" /></p>]]></content><author><name>Pope Kim</name></author><category term="personal" /><category term="google-fanboy" /><category term="vancouver" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I didn't know Google+'s Auto Awesome mode does snow effects too. It was a pleasant surprise to find out what it did to a picture I took recently. It would make a good x-mas card :)]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blog.popekim.com/en/en/assets/img/2013/12/00.gif" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://blog.popekim.com/en/en/assets/img/2013/12/00.gif" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How Much Canadian Programmers Make</title><link href="https://blog.popekim.com/en/2013/12/10/how-much-canadian-programmers-make.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How Much Canadian Programmers Make" /><published>2013-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://blog.popekim.com/en/2013/12/10/how-much-canadian-programmers-make</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.popekim.com/en/2013/12/10/how-much-canadian-programmers-make.html"><![CDATA[<p>I didn't know that Canada government publishes the salary survey information for programmers until today. But here it is.. this shows how much we, Canadian programmers, make for each region.</p>

<p>http://www.workingincanada.gc.ca/LMI_report_bynoc.do?&amp;noc=2173&amp;reportOption=wage</p>

<p>This shows low, median, high hourly wages and the data is pretty up-to-date. (for example, BC stat is from 2011-2012). To calculate the annual salary out of this, simply use this formula:</p>

<p><strong><em>hourly wage * 40 (hr/wk) * 52 (wk) =</em></strong></p>

<p>Alberta, the oil nation, comes in first, followed by BC and ON. If you are my neighbour living in BC, you should make:</p>

<ul>
  <li>low: $44,990</li>
  <li>median: $79,997</li>
  <li>high: $131,997</li>
</ul>

<p>So are you making enough? :P</p>]]></content><author><name>Pope Kim</name></author><category term="personal" /><category term="game-industry" /><category term="money" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I didn't know that Canada government publishes the salary survey information for programmers until today. But here it is.. this shows how much we, Canadian programmers, make for each region.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">[Curiosity Research] Pet Fox</title><link href="https://blog.popekim.com/en/2013/06/10/pet-fox.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="[Curiosity Research] Pet Fox" /><published>2013-06-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-06-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://blog.popekim.com/en/2013/06/10/pet-fox</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.popekim.com/en/2013/06/10/pet-fox.html"><![CDATA[<p>During this weeked, I stumbled into the following video showing a pet fox.</p>

<div class="embed-container">
    <iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fo5OfvqSlKU" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</div>

<p>I was like.. "Really? You can have a pet fox?". So I called my brother, Google, and did some reasearch. And yeah it's possible while it's quite restrictive. This PopSci article, posted in Oct 2012, explains it very well.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.popsci.com/science/article/2012-10/fyi-domesticated-foxes">Popular Science Article: Can I Have A Pet Fox?</a></p>

<p><strong>Short Summary:</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li>There's distinction between tamed and domesticated animals</li>
  <li>You can tame animals by training them since they were young. So if you tame an wild fox, she won't bite you, but she won't play with you. In other words, no ball chasing.. no belly rubbing… no wiggling. Most importantly, the offsprings of tamed animals need to be tamed again.</li>
  <li>Domesticated animals are the result from very selective breeding of "human-friendly" wild foxes. They act more like dogs. It's in their DNA, so their children will love you too :)</li>
  <li>The only way you can buy domesticated foxes are from Russia. They've been doing this selective breeding since 1950s, so after tens of generations those foxes are really dog-like.</li>
  <li>The price is about $6,000</li>
  <li>One interesting thing though: those domesticated foxes are showing some physical difference from pure wild counterparts.</li>
</ul>

<p>so that is today's dose of my curiosity… :P</p>]]></content><author><name>Pope Kim</name></author><category term="personal" /><category term="animal" /><category term="pet" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[During this weeked, I stumbled into the following video showing a pet fox.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/fo5OfvqSlKU/maxresdefault.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://img.youtube.com/vi/fo5OfvqSlKU/maxresdefault.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Random thought on 1080+P</title><link href="https://blog.popekim.com/en/2013/05/18/random-thought-on-1080p.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Random thought on 1080+P" /><published>2013-05-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-05-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://blog.popekim.com/en/2013/05/18/random-thought-on-1080p</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.popekim.com/en/2013/05/18/random-thought-on-1080p.html"><![CDATA[<p>some random thought I had while sitting on a bench at a rainy park today….</p>

<p>I finally watched James Cameron's Avatar the other day on DVD. It was a good movie, but the DVD quality was not that great on my 1080p display. It's after all 480P right? Now people are used to 1080P, so DVD quality wouldn't cut it. (even youtube video looks better than DVD, jesus!)</p>

<p>So then what's next? will we need anything over 1080p? I believe the common belief was that our eyes can't process more than a few million pixels so going over 1080p would be waste.(1080P is about 2 million pixels) <a href="https://plus.google.com/+YesIKnowThat/posts/LToL7NFHU4r">But apparently we can perceive way more than that….</a> So we will need more than 1080P.</p>

<p>But one day TV resolutions will overcome our eyes' capabilitiesright? Then can we stop adding more pixels on the TV? I don't think our eyes are the limit.. the manufacturing cost would be the deciding factor.. Say our eyes can only process 1,000 million pixels. But if we are given a TV with 4,000 million pixels, our eyes will see 4 pixels as one pixel. right? So it would be same as blending those 4 pixels into 1. Oh sweet! it's a 4X super sampling antialiasing! If it's gets 16,000 million pixels it's 16x SSAA.. I can't say no to this.. :)</p>

<p>But as I said, it might become too expensive to add that many pixels one day… but price of LEDs are going down everyday and smart people are making LEDs use less power. so that might not be a problem…. or it might become physically impossible to add more pixels one day? just like how we coudln't make single-core CPUs faster anymore? Maybe…. but still 576 Million pixels are long way to go….</p>]]></content><author><name>Pope Kim</name></author><category term="personal" /><category term="graphics" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[some random thought I had while sitting on a bench at a rainy park today….]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Surviving Winter in Montreal - Snowfall - ALOT</title><link href="https://blog.popekim.com/en/2012/12/28/surviving-winter-in-montreal-snowfall.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Surviving Winter in Montreal - Snowfall - ALOT" /><published>2012-12-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-12-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://blog.popekim.com/en/2012/12/28/surviving-winter-in-montreal-snowfall</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.popekim.com/en/2012/12/28/surviving-winter-in-montreal-snowfall.html"><![CDATA[<p>So yesterday we had some snow.. I mean.. somewhat alot…. 45 to 50 Cm a day. fun eh?</p>

<p>First I shoveled the pathway in front of my house… it took me about 30 mins.</p>

<p><img src="/en/assets/img/2012/12/00.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Then I moved to my backyard/parking lot. I spent about 2~3 hours to clear 2/3 of the parking lot until I had to go out for my Thursday ritual: pub crawl with one of my buddies here. The city does really good job at cleaning major roads. All those snow piles at the curbside will be removed by city in coming days. I was told it would take about a week this time.</p>

<p><img src="/en/assets/img/2012/12/01.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>One nice thing about having a heavy snow was that there were not many people at the pub. So it was quiet and cozy: just how I like. Yum~</p>

<p><img src="/en/assets/img/2012/12/02.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>So while having a couple of drinks, I asked my friend if it's common to have this much snow. He said <strong>"Yeah, this is decent.."</strong> So I thought 'okay I have to be prepared for worse snowfalls and shoveling'… But… now I'm watching a news while writing this blog post. <a href="http://www.theglobeandmail.com/news/national/montrealers-takes-snow-in-stride-as-storm-smashes-1971-record/article6758046/">It says it was the record high snow fall for a single day in Montreal history</a>. I'm gonna go f**king kick his ass… :P  Oh well, the good news is that now I know i can survive the worst snowfall here.. right?</p>

<p>By the way, I shoveled about 3 more hours today to finish my parking lot.</p>]]></content><author><name>Pope Kim</name></author><category term="personal" /><category term="canada" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[So yesterday we had some snow.. I mean.. somewhat alot…. 45 to 50 Cm a day. fun eh?]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://blog.popekim.com/en/en/assets/img/2012/12/00.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://blog.popekim.com/en/en/assets/img/2012/12/00.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Why Da Hell Am I Inventing the Wheel Again?</title><link href="https://blog.popekim.com/en/2012/07/11/why-da-hell-am-i-inventing-wheel-again.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why Da Hell Am I Inventing the Wheel Again?" /><published>2012-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://blog.popekim.com/en/2012/07/11/why-da-hell-am-i-inventing-wheel-again</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.popekim.com/en/2012/07/11/why-da-hell-am-i-inventing-wheel-again.html"><![CDATA[<p>My goal of this week: finishing the Screen Space Decal presentation that I'll give out at Siggraph 2012. If it was purely just making a ppt file I think I would have been more inspired to finish it. The problem is that I'm not with Relic any more and I have no access to their codebase or running editor. So, I'm re-implementing all the features again just to have a demo program where I can take enough screen captures.</p>

<p>It's pretty boring to be honest. I'm not really learning anything by doing this. Just repeating what I already know inside out. Anyways all the feature implementation is done, and some test assets are all placed. So I'll try to finish this week.</p>

<p>I have a couple of interesting projects I wanna work on after this, so I might be able to use that as my motivation to finish the presentation… we will seee…</p>]]></content><author><name>Pope Kim</name></author><category term="personal" /><category term="rants" /><category term="conf" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[My goal of this week: finishing the Screen Space Decal presentation that I'll give out at Siggraph 2012. If it was purely just making a ppt file I think I would have been more inspired to finish it. The problem is that I'm not with Relic any more and I have no access to their codebase or running editor. So, I'm re-implementing all the features again just to have a demo program where I can take enough screen captures.]]></summary></entry></feed>